消灭!
Exterminate!
博士必须被消灭!
The Doctor must be destroyed!
地球由我和我的伙伴们保护，
Earth is protected by me and my mates,
今年，每一年
this year and every other.
我们走!
Here we go!
消灭!
Exterminate!
- 现在安装零件 - 武器失效
- Now attach the parts. - Weapon failure.
- 零件已经装好了，博士! - 快离开这里!
- The parts are on, Doctor! - Get clear!
里面的人都没事吧?
Is everyone all right in there?
里面出了事故
We had an accident.
有人受伤了
People got hurt.
问题已经解决了
The issue's been dealt with.
有人会在23号仓库等着
There'll be someone waiting at Depository 23.
我们很久没开过那个仓库了
Long time since we opened that one.
话说，它安全吗?
Whatever that is, is it safe?
尽快送过去就行
Just get it there quick as you can.
我可以停下来喝杯茶吗?
Am I allowed to stop for a cuppa?
哦，当然可以
Oh, only cos it's you.
顺便问一下，你妈妈怎么样了?
How's your mum, by the way?
- 是啊，你知道… - 一定很辛苦
- Yeah, you know... - Must be hard.
是的最好赶紧上路
Yeah. Best get on the road.
-嗨-嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
能给我来杯茶吗?谢谢你！
Can I get a cup of tea in there, please? Thank you.
- 给你，亲爱的 - 谢谢
- There you go, love. - Cheers.
- 祝你愉快 - 非常感谢祝你过得愉快
- Have a good day. - Thanks very much. Have a good one.
*神秘博士 *
第二季第11集
2021年1月1日
"戴立克的革命"
当你说早餐会议的时候
When you said breakfast meeting,
我想应该是提供早餐的地方
I presumed it would be somewhere that served breakfast.
- Jo Patterson. - Leo Rugazzi.
Rugazzi技术的CEO
CEO, Rugazzi Technologies.
我18个月前收购了Leo的公司
I acquired Leo's company 18 months ago.
我看到你现在买了很多公司
I see you buying a lot of companies right now.
他们叫你美国人迈克·阿什利
They're calling you the American Mike Ashley.
现在市场上有很多值钱的东西
There's a lot of value in the market today.
你的政治野心被毁了
Having your political ambitions ruined
因为那件小小的有毒废物丑闻
by that little toxic waste scandal
塞翁失马焉知非福
seems to have been a blessing in disguise.
这对我来说是个非常敏感的话题
That's a very sensitive subject for me.
我只想说我超兴奋的
I just wanted to say that I am super-psyched
终于有个合适的技术秘书了
about having a proper Technology Secretary at last.
我也非常兴奋，
I was super-psyched too,
直到他们告诉我，我的预算是2.7英镑
until they told me that my budget was £2.70.
如果有人能成功的话，那就是你了，Jo
Well, if anybody can make it work, it's you, Jo.
告诉我为什么我们在这里
Show me why we're here.
Leo有…
Leo has something...
. .革命性的展示给你看
..revolutionary to show you.
来看一场情景演练
Just a small role-play.
我们都知道当今世界面临的问题
We all know the problems facing the world today.
对我们领导人的信任处于历史最低水平
Trust in our leaders is at an all-time low.
国内动乱正在加剧
Civil unrest is growing.
安全预算正在下降
Security budgets are falling.
我们的警察部队承受着压力
Our police forces are under pressure.
天啊，我希望没人会受伤
Goodness, I hope no-one's going to get hurt.
问题是显而易见的
The problem is obvious.
这是我们的解决方案
Here's the solution.
内置高压水枪
Built-in water cannon.
和催泪瓦斯
And CS gas.
实际并没有用催泪瓦斯
We're not using actual CS gas.
我还是觉得这样挺好的
I still think it would have been fine.
声波的威慑!
Sonic deterrent!
完全的机器人与人工智能界面程序
Entirely robotic with an AI interface programme
对于每一个可能发生的事,
for every eventuality,
多亏了广泛的真实场景测试
thanks to extensive real-world scenario testing.
呃,太阳能…太阳能能源等级为a级
Er, solar... solar powered with A-grade energy rating.
你自己建的?
You built this yourself?
哦,差不多嗯,
Oh, pretty much. Um,
一旦罗伯逊介入此事，
once Mr Robertson became involved,
他真的帮助我们推动了整个项目
he really helped us turbo-boost the whole project.
实际上,谈论…
Actually, talking about...
-她知道了，Leo- 这很好
- Er, she gets the picture, Leo. - That's fine.
Jo，这是一个转折点
This is a game-changer, Jo.
它的安全性相当于iPhone
It's the security equivalent of the iPhone.
我们私下谈谈好吗?
Shall we talk in private?
我想让他们在我的选区里建造和测试
I want them built and beta tested in my constituency.
是的，是的，正如讨论过的
Yes, yes, as discussed.
当那些汽车公司抛弃你的时候
When those car firms deserted you,
我买下了所有的植物
I bought up all the plants.
我现在拥有它们所以我们可以重新部署
I own them now. So we repurpose
新的基础设施，新的就业机会
new infrastructure, new jobs.
这对你来说将是一场大胜利，Jo
This is going to be a big win for you, Jo.
这是我们充满活力的新技术秘书制定的旗舰政策
A flagship policy from our dynamic new Technology Secretary
它看起来，呃，
and it looks like, er,
你们党很快就需要一个新领袖了
your party's going to need a new leader soon.
他知道什么，小Leo?
What does he know, young Leo?
我只知道零件是从某个未知的来源得来的
Only that I got the parts from some unknown source.
如果我给你通风报信的事被人知道
If it ever gets out that I tipped you off
关于先进技术从GCHQ传送过来…
about advanced technology being transported from GCHQ...
它不会
It won't.
我们彼此信任
We trust each other.
这是个很好的安排，Jo
This is a good arrangement, Jo.
你只是在促成收购
You're simply facilitating an acquisition
我也会把IP给你
and I'm cutting you in on the IP.
没有人知道
Nobody knows.
每个人都赢了
Everybody wins.
要花多长时间?
How long will it take?
大概一年吧
Er, a year, give or take.
啊…
Ugh...
早上好,相机37
Morning, camera 37.
早上好,相机38
Morning, camera 38.
早上,Angela
Morning, Angela.
好吧，雌雄大盗?
All right, Bonnie and Clyde?
小!
Tiny!
多少次?
How many times?
相信我，你不能逃出去，我试过了
You can't eat the cage. Believe me, I've tried.
睡前故事,博士?
Bedtime story, Doctor?
是的,请,博士
Yes, please, Doctor.
经典名著之一?
One of the classics?
哦,是的,请
Ooh, yes, please.
安定下来
Settle down, then.
家住女贞路4号的德思礼夫妇自豪地说
"Mr and Mrs Dursley, of number four Privet Drive, were proud to say
“他们完全正常……”
"that they were perfectly normal..."
什么?
What?
那里是谁?
Who's there?
保持强劲
Stay strong.
人们在等你
People are waiting for you.
我一直在思考她就在这里待了几分钟
I keep thinking. She was barely in here for a couple of minutes
但她却把我们的DNA编码进了门锁，
and yet she coded the entry lock to our DNA,
就像在她自己的塔迪斯
just like on her own TARDIS.
也许,
Maybe,
那是因为她希望我们能跟踪她，
that's cos she wanted us to be able to follow her,
找到她,
to find her,
因为她需要我们
cos she needed us.
我要把它算出来
I'm going to work it out.
我一定能解决这个问题
I must be able to work it out.
新年快乐，Yaz
Happy New Year, Yaz.
新年是什么时候?
When was it New Year?
你睡在这里?
You been sleeping in here?
也许吧
Maybe.
Yaz
Yaz,
你不能一直待在这里
you can't keep being here all the time.
博士，你知道的，她去做了
The Doc, you know, she went to do
她知道的事可能会要了她的命
something she knew might kill her.
我们只能假设她没能活下来
We've just got to assume she didn't make it.
为什么?
Why?
我们为什么要这样假设呢?
Why do we have to assume that?
伙计，我们已经回来十个月了
Mate, we've been back ten months.
我们得继续我们的生活
We have to get on with our lives.
这是她告诉我们的这就是她想要的
That's what she told us. That's what she wanted for us.
但如果她需要我们呢?
But what if she needs us?
她救过我们多少次了?
How many times has she saved us?
Yaz，面对现实吧，我们不知道怎么找到她
Yaz, face up to it, we don't know how to find her.
好吧?
All right?
还有一件事
And there's something else.
-格雷厄姆，给她看看-嗯嗯
- Graham, show her. - Mm-hm.
博士会很希望我们的
The Doc would really want us
监视这个星球，对吧?
to keep an eye on the planet, right?
听着，这是泄露到网上的录像
Look, this is leaked online footage
他们所谓的安全无人机原型
of what they're calling a prototype security drone.
显然，这是一年前拍的只是看
Apparently, this was taken over a year ago. Just watch.
-那是戴立克-嗯嗯
- That's a Dalek. - Mm-hm.
但这怎么可能呢?
But how's that possible?
不知道手表
No idea. Watch.
杰克罗伯逊
Jack Robertson.
- 蜘蛛人毫米
- Spider guy. - Mm.
他和戴立克是一伙的?
He's in league with a Dalek?
这就是我们要查清楚的
That's what we're going to find out.
如果她在这里，博士也会这么做，所以…
And that's what the Doc would do if she was here, so...
. .你明白我们的意思吗?
..are you with us?
这是我的荣幸
Well, it's an honour
等待被首相召见
to be summoned by the Prime Minister in waiting...
. .即使它有点，呃，乡野气息
..even if it is a bit, er, rural.
离投票结果还有多少小时?
How many hours till we get the results from the ballots?
数据都在我这边
The numbers are on my side.
所以我才想跟你谈谈
That's why I wanted to talk.
你不会对我们的协议有疑问吧?
You're not having doubts about our agreement, are you?
恰恰相反
Quite the opposite.
我想加快我们的项目
I want to expedite our project.
英语中最甜蜜的六个字
Six of the sweetest words in the English language.
我要你们立即在全国范围内部署无人机
I want an immediate national roll-out of security drones.
国家吗?
National?
但我们才刚刚开始区域测试
But we've only just started regional beta testing.
我希望英国纳税人不为此付出任何代价
And I want it at no cost to the British taxpayer.
Jo，这听起来有点像勒索
Why, Jo, this is starting to sound like a shakedown.
这个国家可以成为你全球销售的橱窗
This country can be your shop window for global sales.
当然，除非你想让财政部看看
Unless, of course, you'd like the Treasury to take a look
你们这里的公司要交多少税?
at how much tax all your companies pay over here?
啊好了……
Ah. Well played...
. .首相
..Prime Minister.
好了
Well played.
Leo?我在外面
Leo? I'm outside.
三分钟
Three minutes.
哟还记得我们吗?
Yo. Remember us?
把车!离开我的脸
Take the car! Just leave my face.
什么?
What?
哦,不!
Oh, no!
不是你们!
Not you guys!
对，我们，因为我们知道你和戴立克的事
Yeah, us, cos we know all about you and that Dalek.
什么?戴立克
The what? The Dalek.
宇宙中最致命的生物
The most deadly creature in the universe.
我们看见你拿着它
We saw you with it.
你一直用的是什么词?
What is this word that you keep using?
噢，别装无辜了!戴立克
Oh, don't play innocent! Dalek.
不管你用它做什么，我们都会阻止你的
Whatever you're doing with it, we're going to stop you.
举起手来!离车远点!
Hands in the air! Step away from the car!
怎么，你以为我不会加强安保吗
What, you didn't think I'd increase my security
自从我们上次见面后?
since the last time we met?
你们没死在地上算你们走运了
You're lucky you're not all dead on the ground.
除掉他们，伙计们
Get rid of 'em, boys.
跟计划的不太一样，对吧?
Well, that didn't go exactly to plan, did it?
我喜欢这句"不管你在做什么，
I like that whole "whatever you're doing,
"我们会阻止你"的感觉
"we're going to stop you" vibe.
- 非常Doctory-我这么做的时候没用
- Very Doctory. - Doesn't work when I do it.
我们没有从他那里得到任何解释
We didn't get anywhere near an explanation from him.
如果我们有博士的通灵纸
If we had the Doctor's psychic paper
或者我们知道怎么对付塔迪斯，
or we knew how to work that TARDIS,
我们可以去他办公室看看发生了什么事
we could get into his office and see what's going on.
是啊，但我们不知道，所以我们要去
Yeah, but we don't, so we're going
还得想别的办法
to have to try and figure out another way.
是的这很难，不是吗?
Yeah. This is hard, innit?
早上好,相机38
Morning, camera 38.
哦，我忘了你在这儿
Oh, I forgot you were here.
这张脸怎么样?
What about this face?
还记得这个吗?
Remember this?
杰克?
Jack?
杰克!
Jack!
我就知道你穿这些颜色会比我好看
I knew you would look better in these colours than me.
你好,博士
Hello, Doctor.
你在这里做什么?
What are you doing here?
不然你以为我在这里干什么?打破你
What do you think I'm doing here? Breaking you out.
时间冻结门户去阻泡吸引人的,对吧?
Temporal-freezing gateway disinhibitor bubble. Catchy, right?
换做是我，我会称之为突击手
If it were me, I'd have called it a breakout ball.
暂时冻结时间，打破墙壁
Freezes time temporarily, breaks through walls.
唯一的问题是……
Only problem is...
. .不会持续太久的
..it doesn't last long.
- 你好!-你做过手术吗?
- Hi! - Have you had work done?
你可以说话!
You can talk!
现在闭嘴跑吧
Now shut up and run.
我听说你在这里，所以我犯了几次罪
I heard a rumour you were in here, so I committed a few crimes.
也许是很多犯罪也许比我应该的要多
Well, maybe a lot of crimes. Maybe more than I should have.
什么样的罪行?
What sort of crimes?
- 左拐- 哦!
- Left turn. - Oh!
你要在我面前占据道德高地
You're going to take the moral high ground with me
当我帮你越狱的时候?
when I'm breaking you out of prison?
- 感恩!- 前门!
- Be grateful! - Front door!
-这东西还剩多久?- 11秒后到期!
- How long has this thing got left? - 11 seconds till expiry!
走吧!
Go!
唷!
Phew!
花了19年才进到你旁边的牢房
Took 19 years to get to the cell next to you.
希望你脑子里有足够的东西
Hope you had enough to occupy your mind.
太多了
Too much.
我们开始吧一个秘密藏起来的旋涡操纵器
Here we go. One secretly stashed vortex manipulator.
不知道这需要多长时间我们得走了
Wondered how long that would take. We need to go now.
你是怎么把它偷偷带进来的?
How did you manage to smuggle that in here?
你真想让我回答吗?
You really want me to answer that?
哦，我好想你……非常感谢
Oh, I've missed you... very much.
我们走吧
Let's go.
运营、物流和生产都已纳入
Operation, logistics and production have all been called in.
每个人都被告知最大容量，最大速度，
Everyone has been told maximum capacity, maximum speed,
而我们的贝塔搭档则通宵工作，
and our beta partners are working through the night,
培训员工，在我们的主管-
training staff, under our supervisors -
都是保密协议下的…当然可以
all under NDAs, of... of course.
我们认为我们可能有足够的……
We think we might have enough in place to...
. .嗯，为了赶上最后期限
..well, to make the deadline.
太好了
Great.
伟大的工作,Leo这对我们有好处
Great job, Leo. This is going to be good for us.
我忍不住有点…
I-I can't help but feel a little...
. .你知道的，我有点担心这事的进展速度
..well, you know, a little worried about the speed of this.
每个人都担心,Leo
Everybody's worried, Leo.
我们生活在一个不确定的时代你想赢吗?
We live in uncertain times. Do you want to win?
拥抱不确定
Embrace the uncertainty.
生活在忧虑中
Live in the worry.
O-OK嗯,所以…
O-OK. Um, so...
所以…有些事我想跟你说
So... there's-there's just something I-I needed to share
在这个项目中
on this project.
我刚开始研究弹壳的时候，
When I first started working on that casing,
我把它分解成最小的部分
I broke it down into the tiniest components.
我的任务就是，了解它的一切
I made it my mission to, well, to understand everything about it.
是的，你做得很好
Yes, and you did a great job.
这些机器将会改变
These machines are going to change
- 世界-我说的不是机器
- the world. - I'm not talking about the machines.
我说的是原始藏物里面的东西
I'm talking about what was inside the original artefact.
里面什么都没有，Leo
There's nothing inside, Leo.
那是一个烧坏了的壳
It was a burnt-out shell.
这就是我想告诉你的
Well, that's what I'm trying to tell you.
我一直在做的细致调查，我…
This granular investigation I've been doing, I...
. .我发现了更多的东西
..well, I found something more -
机器内部的有机残留物，
organic remnants inside the machine,
微小的细胞痕迹散布在弹壳上
tiny cellular traces scattered across the casing.
你想说什么，Leo?
Where are you going with this, Leo?
嗯…
Well...
看,我居……我来演示给你们看
Look, I'll ju... I'll just show you.
看
Look.
就在这里,看到了吗?
Just here, see?
我查了手机信号，我…
I-I took the cellular traces and I...
. .然后我克隆了它们
..and I cloned them.
了他们
Grew them.
我培育了一个生物
I grew a creature.
哦,我的上帝!
Oh, my God!
-很漂亮，不是吗?- 不!
- It's beautiful, isn't it? - No!
你疯了吗? !
Are you insane?!
这是我这辈子见过的最恶心的事
That's the most disgusting thing I've ever seen in my life.
你在想什么?
What were you thinking?
什么?这是聪明的
What? It's intelligent.
我把它接入了内部神经网络
I hooked it into the intra-neural network
和…还有一些活动
and... and there were flickers of activity.
它能立即理解我们的系统
It understood our systems immediately.
你做了什么? !
You did what?!
好吧没有另一个词
All right. Not another word.
你不自量力,Leo
You've overreached, Leo.
我要你马上把它烧掉什么? !
I want this incinerated immediately. What?!
没有理由!
No argument!
噢!
Ow!
我不想看到任何痕迹
I don't want to see a trace of this.
这从没发生过，你从没给我看过，
This never happened, you never showed it to me,
这东西根本不存在你明白吗?
this thing never existed. Do you understand?
好吧,好吧
OK, OK.
你知道你的问题在哪吗，Leo?
You know what your problem is, Leo?
你太聪明了
You're too clever.
这就是为什么人们不喜欢专家
This is why people don't like experts.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
嗨,爱
Hi, love.
它……是我
It... It's me.
我今晚有急事要出差
I-I have to go on an urgent business trip tonight.
替我吻孩子们一下
Give the kids a kiss from me.
呃…
Er...
. .我有空的时候给你打电话
..I'll call you when I can.
爱你
Love you.
再见
Bye.
爱你
Love you.
再见
Bye.
的立场
Stand.
良好的傀儡
Good puppet.
我们出去
We're out.
我回来了
I'm back.
我自己的TARDIS
My own TARDIS.
杰克·哈克尼斯船长，救援金星勋章
Captain Jack Harkness, gold star for rescuing.
我告诉过你的朋友如果你需要帮助，我会在你身边
Told your friends if you ever need help, I'd be there.
哇
Wow.
这里升级得不错
Nice upgrade in here.
我的房间往哪边走?
Which way's my room?
你没有房间你从来没有过房间
You don't have a room. You've never had a room.
我有一间带鸡尾酒会的套房
I had a suite with its own cocktail lounge.
他们把我的信息告诉你了，关于那个孤独的赛博人?
They gave you my message, about the lone Cyberman?
你没有给它网络空间?
You didn't give it the Cyberium?
-说来话长我固定它- 什么?
- It's a long story. I fixed it. - What?
最终
Eventually.
差不多排序的
Just about. Sort of.
你一开始为什么要进监狱?
Why were you in prison in the first place?
逃避Judoon一次两次
Evading the Judoon. Twice at once.
当我被录取后，他们又考虑了7000项其他罪行
Then once I was in, they took 7,000 other offences into consideration.
他们7点就停了?
They stopped at seven?
我因为做我自己而进了监狱……
I was in prison for being me...
. .就在我不确定那是什么意思的时候
..right at the point when I wasn't sure what that meant.
这几十年真是难熬啊
Ah, it's been a tough few decades.
你现在没事了，是吗?
You're OK now, yeah?
我想我们会知道的
Oh, I guess we'll find out.
Wakey-wakey
Wakey-wakey.
嘿!
Hey!
好睡吗?
Nice nap?
谢谢你的等待
Thanks for waiting.
我在那里有很多事要考虑
I had a lot to think about in there.
还有三个我想念的特别的人
And three very special people I've missed.
-其中一个就是我，对吧?-你从不改变
- One of them was me, right? - You never change.
真希望我也能这么说
Wish I could say the same.
正确的
Right.
帮我找我的家人
Find me my fam.
这是我目前得到的
This is what I've got so far.
我们在GCHQ对抗的戴立克的残余
Remnants of the Dalek we fought at GCHQ
无罪释放但后来被偷了
were cleared but then stolen.
司机失踪了，估计已经死亡
The driver is missing, presumed dead.
现在罗伯逊已经下手了
Now Robertson's got his hands on it.
他不可能，
Well, he can't have,
因为是你把里面的那个怪物送去的
because you sent that creature thing that was inside it
变成超新星，所以…
into a supernova, so...
也许地球上还有更多
Maybe there's more of them here on Earth.
其中一个控制了罗伯逊
And one's got Robertson under their control.
瑞安,嘘!
Ryan, shh!
请
Please.
请她
Please be her.
这就跟你问声好！我在太空监狱
Hi! I was in space jail.
你什么?
You what?
猜猜是谁把她救出来的?
Guess who got her out?
你们都见过杰克吧?
You all met Jack, right?
嘿,银狐!
Hey, silver fox!
你好
Hello.
我们很担心你!
We were worried about you!
什么?有多久了?
What? How long's it been?
一个星期?
A week?
两个星期吗?
Two weeks?
十个月
Ten months.
呃,哦!
Er, whoops!
不，不可能
No, it can't be.
我设置了相同的时间坐标
I set identical temporal coordinates
我送你回去的时候
to when I sent you back.
是啊，但你的时间机器不是最好的
Yeah, but your time machine ain't the best
在跑时间，是吗，博士?
at running to time, is it, Doc?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
好吧，现在都结束了，所以…
Yeah, well, it's done now, so...
是的
Yeah.
所以…
So...
. .地球上有什么新鲜事吗?
..what's new on planet Earth?
戴立克
Dalek.
前进
Forward.
进一步进一步
Further. Further.
这是什么地方?
What is this place?
你做了什么?
What have you done?
这是我的项目
This is my project.
这是我建造的
This is what I have built.
看起来像戴立克，但不可能是戴立克…
So, it looks like a Dalek, but it can't be a Dalek...
. .除非他是戴立克!
..unless it is a Dalek!
相信我们我们看过录像了
Trust us. We've seen the footage.
如果你在地球上扫描戴立克的DNA
If you scan for Dalek DNA trace across the planet...
-哦，她很好-是的，我们都是
- Oh, she's good. - Yeah, we all are.
这么说，你也和戴立克打过交道?
So, you've had dealings with Daleks as well, then?
是的，他们杀过我一次很久以前了，没什么大不了的
Yeah, they killed me once. Long time ago, no big deal.
-作为一具尸体你看起来很健康-我知道，对吧?
- You look pretty healthy for a corpse. - I know, right?
我可以被杀死，但我很快就会复活
I can be killed but I come back to life pretty quick.
一部分是她的错，一部分是她在地球上的朋友罗斯
Partially her fault, partially a friend of hers on Earth called Rose.
但她现在被困在一个平行宇宙里了
But she's trapped in a parallel universe now.
她是什么?
She's what?
戴立克DNA追踪-日本
Dalek DNA trace - Japan.
大阪嗯,有点不是完全匹配
Osaka. Well, sort of. Not an exact match.
哦,它是损坏的
Oh, it's corrupted.
我不太明白这是什么意思
I can't quite make sense of it.
我可以去看看有人要来吗?
I can check it out. Anyone want to come?
我要!
I will!
-我要和罗伯逊导演谈谈-我也是
- I want a word with Robertson direct. - Yeah, me too.
看来他最近在大阪开了一家机构
Looks like he's recently opened a facility in Osaka.
我们可以去看看，顺便送你过去
We could check it out, drop you on the way.
每个人都在最大限度地工作
Everyone working at maximum capacity.
呃…我回头打给你
Er... Let me call you back.
如果你要对付戴立克，那你就太不自量力了
If you're dealing with Daleks, you are way out of your depth.
那是什么东西?
What is that thing?
我想知道你现在在干什么，
I want to know what you're doing right now,
别打给保安，我刚把你的电话线给屏蔽了
and don't try calling security, cos I just blocked your phone lines.
你们这些人到底怎么了?嗯?
What is the matter with you people? Hmm?
你想知道我在干什么吗?我亲自给你看
Do you want to know what I'm doing? I'll show you myself.
欢迎来到生产线
Welcome to the production line.
你做戴立克
You're making Daleks.
我们是3d打印安全无人机
We're 3D-printing security drones.
-里面的东西呢?-里面什么都没有
- What about what's inside? - There's nothing inside.
它是由人工智能运行的
It's run by artificial intelligence.
- 什么?- 看
- What? - Watch.
看到了吗?
See?
他们的机器
They're machines.
这是远程信号装置
There's the remote signal unit.
- 他们是空的-嗯嗯
- They're empty. - Mm-hm.
你在搅乱你不懂的东西
You're messing with things you don't understand.
这些作品所模仿的生物
The creature these are modelled on
是宇宙中最邪恶的杀人机器
is the most evil killing machine in the universe.
你对一堆3d打印的形状太兴奋了
You're getting much too excited about a bunch of 3D-printed shapes.
你在大阪的工厂里做什么?
So what are you doing at your facility in Osaka?
(我们在大阪没有工厂)
We don't have a facility in Osaka.
-是的，你知道-不，我们不知道!
- Yeah, you do. - No, we don't!
我想知道
I would know.
上面说这是一个农业园区
It says this is an agricultural park.
我猜这就是未来
Guess this is the future.
- 嗯- 垂直农场都在里面
- Hmm. - Vertical farms. All inside.
在我那个年代，有很多像这样的农业行星，
In my time, there are whole agri-planets that look like this,
把食物运送到星系的各个角落
shipping food all over galaxies.
你的时间?第51个世纪
Your time? 51st century.
滚开!
Get lost!
认真对待Boeshane半岛
Seriously. Boeshane Peninsula.
也许有一天我会带你去
Maybe one day I'll take you there.
-他们都像你一样吗?- 没有
- Are they all like you there? - No.
我很特别
I'm pretty special.
过得很艰难，是吗?
Had a rough time, then?
没有看博士吗?
Without the Doctor?
(我不明白你的意思)
I don't know what you mean.
我看到你推她的样子了
I saw the way you shoved her.
你以为她不会回来了，对吗?
You thought she wasn't coming back, right?
你一推就猜了很多
You're guessing a lot from a shove.
我自己也有跟博士打交道的经历
I have my own experience with the Doctor.
我刚好错过了她
I just missed her.
-我从没想过…-嗨
- I never stopped to think... - Hey.
我和博士在一起的时候，我看到
When I was with the Doctor, I-I saw
比我想象的还要多
more than I could have ever dreamed.
然后……
And then...
. .我们失去了彼此
..we lost each other.
我不知道他出了什么事
I didn't know what happened to him.
如果他还活着或者…
If he was alive or...
. .如果我还能再见到他
..if I was ever going to see him again.
生活很艰难
Hard way to live.
和博士在一起，你不能选择什么时候停止…
Being with the Doctor, you don't get to choose when it stops...
. .你是要离开她还是…
..whether you leave her or...
. .她离开你
..she leaves you.
感觉残忍……
It felt cruel...
. .让我看到我不能再拥有的东西
..to be shown something I couldn't have any more.
我觉得，我还是不知道的好
Felt like, um, I'd rather not have known.
我宁愿没有遇见她，因为遇见她之后…
I'd rather not have met her, cos having met her and then...
. .没有她，那更糟
..being without her, that's worse.
你是怎么处理的?
How do you deal with that?
宇宙中有多少人能见到博士，
How many people in the universe get to meet the Doctor,
更别说和她一起旅行了?
let alone travel with her?
我们很幸运，Yaz
We're the lucky ones, Yaz.
享受你的旅程
Enjoy the journey while you're on it.
因为快乐……
Cos the joy...
. .都是值得的
..is worth the pain.
锁着的门
Locked door.
谢谢
Thanks.
“谢谢”吗?
"Thanks"?
就这些吗?
That's it?
你是否感到没有安全感?
Are you feeling insecure?
因为你似乎需要很多赞美
Cos you seem to need a lot of praise.
我做了什么?
Do I?
通过这里
Through here.
这些事情
Those things.
那是我们遇到的戴立克体内的东西
They were what was inside the Dalek we met.
在每个戴立克
Inside every Dalek.
这是一个克隆农场
This is a clone farm.
他们不在这里种植食物，他们…
They're not growing food here, they're...
. .他们培育戴立克
..they're growing Daleks.
作为你们的新首相，我看到了巨大的机遇
As your new Prime Minister, I can see great opportunities ahead
对这个国家
for this country.
在英国，我们从未害怕过未来，
We here in Britain, we've never been afraid of the future,
但我理解我们现在渴望的，是安全感
but I do understand that what we all crave right now, is security.
我们的政治安全，
Security in our politics,
我们工作的保障，
security in our jobs,
我们家庭的安全
security for our families.
我保证，会带来稳定和安全
I pledge, to bring stability and security
我们国民生活的方方面面
to every aspect of our national life.
我们一起努力，就能使这个时代成为安全的时代
Together, we can make this the age of security.
这里发生了什么?
What's happening here?
我们到底在做什么?
What are we actually doing?
去大阪-快!
Going to Osaka - fast!
怎么样?
What about...?
这个蓝色的盒子怎么样?
What about this blue box?
-怎么了?- 这是一个……这是一个门?
- What is it? - It's a... It's a doorway?
这不可能
It can't be.
那是我的走廊
That was my hallway.
我不明白你的意思
I don't understand.
我们要不要跟他解释一下?
Should we explain it to him?
不，看他挣扎更有趣
No, it's more fun watching him struggle.
虽然你很难理解，但这不是你的事
As hard as it is for you to understand, this isn't about you.
这是为了戴立克
This is about Daleks.
请不要再用那个词了它没有任何意义
Please stop using that word. It has no meaning.
是的,确实
Yes, it does.
对数十亿人来说，戴立克意味着仇恨
To billions of people, Dalek means hate.
戴立克是充满仇恨和攻击性的生物
Daleks are creatures of hate and aggression.
戴立克阴险无情又聪明
Daleks are insidious, relentless and clever,
而且，就像仇恨一样，如果不加以制止，它们就会扩散
and, like hate, they will spread if they're not stopped.
永远不要低估戴立克
Never underestimate a Dalek.
所以我今天才要揭牌吗
Which is why I am unveiling today
这是一个非常令人兴奋的老问题的新解决方案
a very exciting, new solution to an age-old problem.
我们将利用技术革命来提高您的安全
We will harness the technological revolution to enhance your safety.
我们会减轻警察和保安人员的压力
We will alleviate pressure on police and security staff
这一切都没有掏空公众的钱包
and all without draining the public purse.
Oi !
Oi!
你能快点帮我吗?
Can you hurry up and help me with this?
我需要提取液体的样本
I need to take a sample of the liquid.
我想知道它吃的是什么
I want to know what it's being fed on.
也许能给我们一些阻止他们的线索
Might give us a clue on how to stop 'em.
嗯我们要把他们炸了，孩子
Huh. We're going to blow 'em up, kid.
这样才能阻止他们
That's how we stop 'em.
杰克!
Jack!
把它拿开!
Get it off me!
站着不动!,别动!
Stand still! Yaz, don't move!
漂亮的照片
Nice shot.
到现在为止，你会看到新的防御无人机在工作
As of now, you will see new defence drones at work
英国的街道上……
on Britain's streets...
. .在我们的机构里，在我们的边界…
..in our institutions, at our borders...
. .和国家纪念碑
..and national monuments.
这些技术革新是既定的
These technological innovations are set
让英国更安全
to make Britain more secure.
你确实喜欢无檐帽
You do love a beanie.
我也是
Me too.
我们相遇那晚，我注意到你的第一件事
One of the first things I noticed about you that night we met.
我想，不是每个人都能拿着黄色的无檐帽
I thought, "Not everyone can carry off a yellow beanie.
“有个小伙子可以依靠”
"There's a lad to rely on."
4分钟到大阪
Four minutes to Osaka.
是的好的
Yeah. OK.
我很抱歉……
I'm sorry...
. .大约十个月
..about the ten months.
我的遗憾无以言表
More sorry than I can ever really say.
这个东西,不是吗?你从来没有真正掌握它的窍门
This thing, innit? You never really quite got the hang of it.
我想念你们……
I missed you all...
. .这么多
..so much.
是吗?
Yeah?
我们也很想你
We missed you too.
但你一直很好吗?
But you've been good?
-是啊，也许这就是我需要的-哦,是的嗯
- Yeah, maybe it's what I needed. - Oh, yeah. Huh.
也许是
Maybe it was.
嗯我看见我爸爸了
Hmm. I saw me dad.
哦,很好嗯，好吃吗?
Oh, good. Well, was it good?
他是好吗?
He's all right?
是的，他又回石油钻塔去了
Yeah, he's back at the oil rigs again.
几周后回来
Due back in a couple of weeks.
但是，是的，我们很好我们到达那里
But, yeah, we're good. We're getting there.
是时候和他联系了，是时候见我了，
Time to reconnect with him, time to see me mates,
看看这个古老的星球上发生了什么
see what's happening on the old planet.
在地球上有很多工作要做
Lots of work to be done here on Earth.
是的总是这样
Yeah. Always.
听起来你很享受回来的感觉
Well, it sounds like you enjoyed being back.
它的家
It's home.
是的
Yeah.
你的家怎么了?
What's happening with your home?
你在伽里弗雷上发生了什么?
You know, what happened to you on Gallifrey?
那里所有的生命都被毁灭了
All life there destroyed.
多亏了死亡粒子和柯·沙莫斯
Thanks to the death particle and Ko Sharmus.
和主吗?他找你干什么?
And the Master? What did he want with you?
现在都不重要了不,不,不
It doesn't even matter now. No, no, no.
别跟我胡扯对吧?我知道你在做什么
Don't give me that. Right? I see what you're doing.
你在试图回避这个话题
You're trying to avoid the subject.
我们已经认识够久了
We've known each other long enough now.
我知道什么时候发生了变化
I know when something's changed.
我也是
Me too.
我不是我以为的那个人，莱恩
I'm not who I thought I was, Ryan.
我一直知道的我生命的故事…
What I always knew to be the story of my life...
. .不是真实的
..isn't true.
我不是在伽里弗雷出生的
I wasn't born on Gallifrey.
我的家乡，我的生活，
Where I'm from, all the lives I've lived,
有些事一直瞒着我，我甚至不知道到底有多少
some of that has been hidden from me, and I don't even know how much.
严重吗?
Seriously?
你对此有何感想?
And how do you feel about that?
主要是…
Mostly...
. .生气
..angry.
当我被关起来的时候，我一直在想…
While I was locked away, all I kept thinking, was...
“如果我不是我想的那样，那我是谁?”
"If I'm not who I thought I was, then who am I?"
你是博士
You're the Doctor.
一如既往，一如既往
Same as before, same as always.
正确的
Right.
同样的博士，同样的瑞恩
Same Doctor, same Ryan.
什么都没有改变
Nothing's changed.
不不
No. No.
我没那么说，对吧?
I didn't say that, did I?
事情一直在变化，
Things change all the time,
他们应该这么做，因为他们必须这么做
and they should, cos they have to.
与人相同
Same with people.
有时候我们会有点害怕，因为新来的人会有点害怕，对吧?
Sometimes we get a bit scared, cos new can be a bit scary, right?
新东西会很吓人
New can be very scary.
等我们解决了戴立克的问题，
So, when we're done with this Dalek problem,
你发现了自己的生活
you find out about your own life.
面对新事物或旧事物
Confront the new, or the old.
然后一切都会好起来的
And then everything will be all right.
- MWill吗?- 毫无疑问
- MWill it? - No doubt.
什么?
What?
谢谢你,瑞恩……
Thank you, Ryan...
. .感谢你做我的朋友
..for being my friend.
谢谢你成为我的人
Thank you for being mine.
总是这样
Always.
大阪
Osaka.
Oh-ho-ho !我错过了那个声音
Oh-ho-ho! I've missed that sound.
哇!
Whoa!
等等，刚才发生了什么?
Wait, what just happened?
还是不告诉他?不
Still not telling him? No.
我在哪儿?
Where am I?
你一定要带他来吗?
Did you really have to bring him?
- Yaz !- 格雷厄姆
- Yaz! - Graham.
哦，那些是什么东西?
Oh, what are those things?
住在戴立克体内的生物
The creatures that live inside Daleks.
但这一切是谁建造的?
But who built all this?!
我有
I have.
Leo?别靠得太近!
Leo? Don't get too close!
我警告过你的
I warned you about that thing.
你做了什么，Leo?
What have you done, Leo?
克隆出最小的有机物质，
Cloned the smallest trace of organic material,
不理解戴立克的意识
not understanding that Dalek consciousness
能活在他们DNA中最微小的片段里
can live within the tiniest fragment of their DNA.
你不知道
You weren't to know.
你是安全的我们为你而来
You're safe. We're here for you.
我们会把你活着救出去的
We're going to get you out of here alive.
你给了这具尸体错误的希望
You give this body false hope.
好吧，戴立克，不管你是谁，
All right, then, Dalek, or whatever you are,
告诉我这一切是怎么来的
tell me how you've built all this.
我把自己接入了神经网络
I connected myself into the neural network.
我融入了这个组织，融入了每一个网络
I inserted myself into the organisation, into every network.
我找到了这个地方，创造了它
I located this place, created it.
每一件设备，背后的每一个想法…
Every piece of equipment, every idea behind it...
. .我这么做
..I did that.
等一下首先，这不可能
Wait a minute. First of all, that's not possible.
你从哪里得到采购订单号的?
Where did you get the purchase order numbers in the first place?
真的吗，你现在最烦的就是这个吗?
Really, that's what's bugging you most right now?
我用你们的系统买了这栋楼，订购了设备，
I used your systems to buy this building, to order equipment,
付钱给人类建造并继续克隆人的工作
to pay humans to construct and to continue the clone work.
我用你们的系统建立了一支以我为原型的军队
I used your systems to build an army all in my image.
但是工人在哪里呢?
But where are the workers?
做克隆的人在哪里?
Where are the people who did all the cloning?
一旦实验成功，它们就变成了……
Once the experiments were working, they became...
不必要的
..unnecessary.
我们发现了它们的另一个用途
We found them another use.
怎么，你在喂克隆人戴立克吗?
What, you're feeding cloned Dalek creatures liquidised humans?
正确的
Correct.
这是公关灾难
This is a PR disaster.
但还有一件事困扰着我
But there's something else that's bugging me.
它是什么?是因为灯光吗?
What is it? Is it the light?
自从我们来到这里，光线就一直变化得很慢
The light's been changing really slowly ever since we've been here.
-是的谢谢,Yaz-我想你，Yaz
- Yes, it is. Thanks, Yaz. - I missed you, Yaz.
为什么这很重要?
Right, why is that important?
-发生的事太多了-我说到哪儿了?
- Oh, there's too much going on. - Where was I?
是的你打算怎么离开这个星球?
Yes. How are you going to get off this planet?
我们不会
We will not.
我很抱歉?
I'm sorry?
地球是我们的它将被转换
The planet is ours. It will be converted.
转换成什么?
Converted into what?
我们要把这个星球当作基地
We shall use this planet as a base
以此来征服宇宙的这一部分
from which to conquer this sector of the universe.
蹲在日本的实验室里还有很长的路要走
There's a long way between squatting in a Japanese lab
人类和征服
and subjugating humanity.
我是说，你连身体都没有
I mean, you don't even have bodies.
你打算做什么？从你的坦克里命令人?
What are you going to do? Order people from your tanks?
即使你在下面找到了那些炮弹，你也做不到
Even if you made it to those shells down there, which you can't.
你不能
You can't.
我是说，你绝对不能…
I mean, you definitely can't. The...
这些炮弹甚至都不是武器他们不是真正的戴立克
Those shells aren't even weaponised. They're not proper Daleks.
-是他造的-博士…
- He built them. - Doctor...
. .有什么事吗?
..what's the matter?
光
The light.
这些炮弹是在他的工厂里制造的
The shells were built in his factories.
你以为我没有扩充那些设计吗?
Do you think I've not augmented those designs also?
光在哪里?我们得把灯关掉!
Where's the light? We have to turn off the light!
为什么,博士?
Why, Doctor?
紫外线
Ultraviolet light.
侦察戴立克用它重新团结起来
The Recon Dalek used it to come back together.
激活!
Activate!
我的计划将会完成
My project shall be complete.
新的戴立克军队只有一个目的
The New Dalek Army shall have but one purpose.
消灭!
Exterminate!
看起来是有一些初期的问题
It appears that there are some teething issues with
…无人机,
the... with the drones,
所以我呼吁大家保持冷静
so I appeal to everybody to keep calm.
无人机完全在我们的控制之下，
The drones are completely under our control,
-所以我们在努力关闭它们…- 领土领袖
- so we're working to shut them down... - Territorial leader
识别
identified.
戴立克不会被关闭的
Daleks will not be shut down.
戴立克是最高的
Daleks are supreme.
这一定是在开玩笑
This must be some sort of a joke.
戴立克可不会开玩笑
Daleks do not joke.
-我不会投降- 消灭!
- And I do not surrender. - Exterminate!
这片土地属于戴立克
This territory is the property of the Daleks.
戴立克控制了一切
Daleks are in control.
所有的人类都将被消灭
All humanity will be exterminated.
-你造了多少戴立克?-我也不知道
- How many Daleks did you build? - Look, I don't know.
- 有多少?- 成千上万!
- How many?! - Thousands!
停止
Stop.
你没必要杀他
You don't have to kill him.
正确的
Correct.
我不需要，但是…
I do not have to, and yet...
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
哦,Leo!
Oh, Leo!
没有武器没时间想了
No weapons. No time to think.
在牢房里待了那么久，想知道我是谁
All that time in a cell wondering who I am.
我是博士
I'm the Doctor.
我是阻止戴立克的人
I'm the one who stops the Daleks.
所有人，去塔迪斯!
All of you, to the TARDIS now!
我只能想到一件事核选项
Only one thing I can think of. Nuclear option.
核选项可能会适得其反
Nuclear option that might backfire.
如果我觉得你是这么想的，
If it's what I think you're thinking,
你现在最好别再想了
you'd better stop thinking it right now.
这风险太大了
Way too big a risk.
-风险有多大?- Planet-threatening
- How big a risk? - Planet-threatening.
有更好的主意吗?因为现在是你的时刻
Got any better ideas? Cos now is your moment.
我洗耳恭听
I'm all ears.
- 嗯- 到底!
- Mmm. - Exactly!
那你打算怎么做?
So, what is it you're going to do?
它们是由最初的侦察戴立克建造的
They're built from the original Reconnaissance Dalek.
我要把他们想要的给他们
I'm going to give them what they wanted in the first place.
-她在干什么?-你永远不想做的事
- What's she doing? - Something you never want to do.
博士，你做了什么?
Doc, what have you done?
通过时间线向漩涡发送了一条信息，
Sent a message through the timelines into the vortex,
因为我知道它们在里面，就像水里的鲨鱼
cos I know they're in there, like sharks in water.
总是确定范围，总是准备好
Always scoping, always ready.
探测到来袭的侦察信号
Incoming reconnaissance signal detected.
Strategise !
Strategise!
“地球目的地”计划
Programme destination for Earth.
预料会有抵抗!
Resistance must be expected!
准备好攻击编队协议!
Ready attack formation protocols!
谁在那里?
Who's in there?
你永远不想看到的飞船到达了你的星球
The ship you never want to see arriving on your planet.
-里面有什么?-敢死队戴立克
- What's on it? - Death Squad Daleks.
就当他们是戴立克的特种空勤团
Think of them like the SAS of Daleks.
-只会更残忍-现在他们是我们最大的希望
- Only way more brutal. - They're our best hope right now.
但他们会杀更多的人类
But they're going to kill more humans.
他们不关心人类
They don't care about humans.
他们是戴立克种族的执行者
They're the enforcers of the Dalek race.
为了对抗戴立克，你带来了更多戴立克?
To combat Daleks, you've brought more Daleks?
是的，但他们不知道我在后面，
Yes, but they don't know that I'm behind the transmission,
让他们不知道我在这里，这很重要
and it's quite important that they don't realise I'm here.
我们有之前我们不是最好的朋友
We've got previous. We're not best mates.
好吧，如果你的计划成功了
All right, look, so if your plan works
而这群戴立克杀死了他的同类…
and this set of Daleks kills his lot...
-这不是我的命-谢谢
- It's not my lot. - Thank you.
. .我们要怎么摆脱新的?
..how do we get rid of the new ones?
这是计划的第二阶段就靠我们了
That's phase two of the plan. It'll be down to us.
虚弱的人类，不要跑!
Feeble humans, do not run!
你们的身体对戴立克来说太慢了!
Your bodies are too slow for Daleks!
戴立克控制了这片领土!
Daleks are in control of this territory!
人类应该被消灭!
Humans shall be exterminated!
新的戴立克军队已经控制住了!
The New Dalek Army is in control!
戴立克重生!
Daleks are reborn!
没有什么能阻止新戴立克军队的霸权!
Nothing shall stop the supremacy of the New Dalek Army!
分析!
Analysis!
扫描确定下面的盗贼生物!
Scan determines rogue creatures below!
检测到变异的戴立克DNA !
Mutated Dalek DNA detected!
准备大灭绝吧!
Prepare for maximum extermination!
主要流氓杂质已定位!
Primary rogue impurities located!
隔离并拦截主要的流氓戴立克杂质!
Isolate and engage primary rogue Dalek impurities!
寻找并摧毁所有戴立克的杂质!
Seek and destroy all other Dalek impurities!
与头号流氓戴立克杂质交战!
Engaging primary rogue Dalek impurities!
停止呆在那儿别动!
Halt. Stay where you are!
-现在是戴立克在控制!- 控制!
- Daleks are now in control! - In control!
在控制!
In control!
戴立克已经掌控了一切
Daleks are already in control.
确定!
Identify!
戴立克!
Dalek!
不正确的扫描检测异常
Incorrect. Scan detects anomalies.
戴立克的DNA和人类的痕迹融合了
Dalek DNA merged with human traces.
我们为了生存而变异
We have mutated to survive.
你是肮脏的!戴立克种族必须拥有纯洁!
You are impure! The Dalek race must have purity!
消灭!
Exterminate!
消灭杂质!
Exterminate the impurities!
-清除杂质!-清除杂质!
- Exterminate the impurities! - Exterminate the impurities!
这就是戴立克的特点
That's the thing about Daleks.
作为一个由基因突变而来的种族，他们对纯洁性非常着迷
For a race born out of mutation, they're pretty obsessed with purity.
所有的产品
All that product.
也许我可以向保险公司提出索赔
Maybe I can make a claim on insurance.
回塔迪斯去
Get back in the TARDIS.
我不听你的命令，博士
I don't take my orders from you, Doctor.
它们是强大而聪明的生物
Those are powerful, intelligent creatures.
我支持他们
I'm backing them.
别傻了他们会杀了你的
Don't be stupid. They will kill you.
我不这么想
I don't think so.
再见
See you later.
罗伯逊，回来!
Robertson, get back here!
- 消灭!- 等待,等待
- Exterminate! - Wait, wait.
我是为和平而来
I come in peace.
你是谁?
Who are you?
我代表人类说话
I speak for humanity.
你是这个星球的领袖吗?
You are the leader of this planet?
是的
Yes.
我是你最好的盟友
And I'm your best ally here.
戴立克不需要盟友
Daleks do not need allies.
我知道地球是怎么运转的
I know how the Earth works.
我有信息
I have information.
我可以指导你
I can guide you.
戴立克不需要人类的指导
Daleks have no need of guidance from humans.
你是不重要的
You are unimportant.
我知道你会这么想，但是，我不是普通人
I can see how you might think that, but, er, I'm no ordinary human.
我们要摧毁戴立克的杂质!
We shall destroy Dalek impurities!
当然可以
Of course.
但当你做完这些，
But when you're done with that,
你也会想要这个星球的，对吧?
you're going to want the planet too, right?
你不觉得你的戴立克同伴会接受吗?
Don't you think that would go down well with your fellow Daleks?
你要背叛自己的种族?
You would betray your own race?
你要背叛人类?
You would betray humanity?
确定
Sure.
我还有一些其他的信息
And I have some other information.
把你带到这里的信号…
The signal that brought you here...
解释!
Explain!
首先，我想认识一下这里的负责人
First, I want to meet who's in charge here.
换句话说，带我去见你们的领袖
In other words, take me to your leader.
计划的第一阶段正在进行
Phase one of the plan is working -
戴立克摧毁其他戴立克
Daleks destroying other Daleks
为了拯救人类
in order to save humanity.
现在,第二阶段
Now, phase two.
杰克，你想登上SAS戴立克的飞船吗?
Jack, how do you feel about boarding an SAS Dalek ship?
-我能把它吹起来吗?- 是的,请
- Can I blow it up? - Yes, please.
我的计划
My kind of plan.
-我有戴立克的问题- 真的吗?
- I have Dalek issues. - No kidding?
你永远不会忘记你的第一次死亡
You never forget your first death.
我和格雷厄姆跟你一起去
Me and Graham are coming with you.
我们是- - - ?-戴立克的飞船，只有一个人
- Are we? - Big Dalek ship, only one guy.
如果我们不帮忙，人类就会灭亡
If we don't help, the human race is going down.
是的，是的，他说得对我们和你一起去
Yeah, yeah, he's right. We're coming with you.
哇，哇，你不介意吧?
Whoa, whoa, are you OK with this?
就算我想，也阻止不了他们
I couldn't stop them even if I wanted to.
在我们确定之前不能爆炸
No detonation until we're sure
特种空勤团戴立克摧毁了罗伯逊所有的创造物
that the SAS Daleks have destroyed all of Robertson's creations.
显然在你们离开戴立克的飞船之前
And before you're all clear of the Dalek ship, obviously.
很明显我们走了这么远不是为了被消灭
Obviously. We didn't come this far just to get exterminated.
好吧,男孩抓住
OK, boys. Hold tight.
因为我们开始了
Cos here we go.
正确的
Right.
指挥中心在那边
OK, command centre is down that way.
不要走那条路大多数戴立克都会在那里
Do not go that way. That's where most of the Daleks will be.
-你知道该怎么做吗?-是的
- Are you clear on what to do? - Yeah.
把这些东西摊开，别送命
Spread these things out and don't get killed.
- 就是这样祝你好运- 嗯-哦…
- That's it. Good luck. - Uh. - Oh...
就是这样,不是吗?瑞安，看，这是我们的专长
That's it, eh? Ryan, see, this is our area of expertise.
先是网络男，现在是戴立克
First, the Cyber dudes, now the Daleks -
没有一艘外星飞船能躲过我们两个坏小子
no alien ship is safe from us two bad boys.
什么?
What?
别这么奇怪了，格雷厄姆
Stop talking weird, Graham.
对不起
Sorry.
警报!船舶内部传感器报告
Alert! Internal ship sensors report
船上有非戴立克生命!
non-Dalek life forms on board!
寻找，定位并消灭所有非戴立克生物!
Seek, locate and exterminate all non-Dalek life forms!
好的!这里谁负责?
OK! Who's in charge here?
我只想和老板说话
I only want to talk to the boss.
说!
Speak!
首先，你得知道我是站在你这边的
Well, first of all, you need to know that I'm on your side.
为了证明这一点，我可以告诉你
Now, to prove that, I can tell you this -
你们正走向一个陷阱
you're all headed into a trap.
叫你来的那个人，她叫你博士
The person who summoned you, she's called the Doctor.
博士是戴立克种族的敌人!
The Doctor is an enemy of the Dalek race!
我知道所以，事情是这样的
I know. So, here's the deal.
你放我一命，我帮你找到她
You let me live, I help you find her.
你在开玩笑吧!
You've got to be kidding me!
紧急空间转移!消灭!
Incoming emergency spatial shift! Exterminate!
不消灭我是戴立克停止!
Do not exterminate. I am Dalek. Halt!
我们清除了所有的杂质!
We have exterminated all impurities!
你是最后的不洁净!
You are the final remaining impurity!
我不是不纯洁的
I am not impure.
我是一个幸存者
I am a survivor -
一名侦察员的最后遗骸
the last remains of a reconnaissance scout.
我调查了这个星球
I surveyed this planet.
我试图通知舰队
I attempted to alert the fleet.
我为戴立克的事业鞠躬尽瘁
I have served, given my life for the Dalek cause.
但你们是不洁净的
But you are impure.
我可以得到净化
I can be purified.
我的基因可以被修改
My genetics can be modified.
只有一种净化
There is only one purification.
消灭!
Exterminate!
啊!杰克，炸药都放好了好了
Argh! Jack, explosives all laid. Good to go.
- 的-什么意思?
- Sort of. - What do you mean?
博士，我有好消息和坏消息
Doctor, I've got some good news and some bad news.
好消息是
The good news is
罗伯逊最后一个戴立克已经被摧毁了
the last of Robertson's Daleks has been destroyed.
我们能不能停一下，假装没有坏消息?
Can we stop there and pretend there's no bad news?
坏消息是罗伯逊正在和戴立克谈判
The bad news is Robertson is negotiating with the Daleks
却出卖了你
and has sold you out.
戴立克知道是你把他们带到这里的，把他们当做陷阱
The Daleks know it was you who brought them here, as a trap.
我就知道我不喜欢这个坏消息
I knew I wouldn't like the bad news.
我们该怎么办?
What do we do?
好吧，我只是看一遍选项…
Right, just running through the options...
. .这没花多长时间
..which hasn't taken long.
即使我们把船炸了，
Even if we blow up the ship,
SAS戴立克还在地球上空肆虐，
there's still SAS Daleks marauding through Earth's skies,
现在他们知道我在这里!
and now they know I'm here!
所以我们得让你远离他们
So we have to keep you out their way.
还是……
Or...
还是别的什么?
Or what?
嘘工作博士,告诉我
Shh. Working. Doctor, tell me.
这件事上你得相信我，Yaz
You're going to have to trust me on this, Yaz.
我什么时候让你失望过?
When have I ever let you down before?
我不会再消失了
I won't disappear again.
是的,你会的
Yeah, you will.
总有一天，你会的
One day, you will.
我们在哪里?
Where are we?
好的，过来监视这个计时器
Right, come here and monitor this timer.
杰克，我需要你准备好让所有人离开那艘飞船然后引爆
Jack, I need you to be ready to get everyone off that ship and detonate.
Yaz会告诉你什么时候
Yaz will tell you when.
那其他戴立克呢?
What about the other Daleks?
我正在对付他们!
I'm dealing with them!
嘿
Hey.
-我有点迷路了警报,警报!
- I'm a bit lost. - Alert, alert!
没有听起来不错你要去接电话吗?
Didn't sound good. Do you want to get that?
留在这里
Remain here.
所有戴立克单位，到中央控制中心报到
All Dalek units, report to central control.
博士被发现了!
The Doctor is detected!
灭绝的形成、组装!
Extermination formations, assemble!
TARDIS位置确定!
TARDIS location identified!
给我们一个要救你的理由
Give us one good reason why we should save your life.
钱吗?
Money?
-我还是认为我们应该把他留在这里-是的
- I still say we should leave him here. - Yeah.
消灭!
Exterminate!
走吧!
Go!
博士的塔迪斯已经找到了围绕着TARDIS !
The Doctor's TARDIS is located. Surround the TARDIS!
嘿!戴立克!
Hey! Daleks!
- 在这里!- 是博士!
- Over here! - It is the Doctor!
博士是戴立克的敌人!
The Doctor is an enemy of the Daleks!
是的,它是是的，我是
Yes, it is. And, yes, I am.
我叫你来，你来了，就像听话的小宠物
I called you here and you came, like obedient little pets.
谢谢你解决了我的问题
Thanks for solving my problem.
戴立克不是博士的宠物!
Daleks are not pets of the Doctor!
是的,你是为什么?你打算怎么做?
Yes, you are. Why? What are you going to do about it?
因为我就站在这里，在我的塔迪斯里
Cos I'm just standing here, in my TARDIS.
攻击TARDIS !消灭博士!
Attack the TARDIS! Exterminate the Doctor!
你确定这条路对吗?
You're sure this is the right way?
-到处都是戴立克!-我们得赶紧离开这里
- There's Daleks everywhere! - We've got to get us out of here.
你是入侵者!
You are intruders!
这是一次可怕的营救!
This is a terrible rescue!
入侵者的位置!生命形式确认!
Intruders located! Life forms identified!
我们包围!
We're surrounded!
-别动!-别动!
- Do not move! - Do not move!
嘿，准备好了吗?我引爆吗?
Hey, are we ready? Do I detonate?
几乎抓住
Almost. Grab hold.
现在,杰克!下船!
Now, Jack! Get off the ship!
入侵者,确定!
Intruders, identify!
我是杰克·哈克尼斯船长我是不朽的哈!
I'm Captain Jack Harkness. And I'm immortal. Ha!
消灭!
Exterminate!
戴立克工艺摧毁!
Dalek craft destroyed!
博士在哪里?!
Where is the Doctor?!
搜索TARDIS !消灭博士!
Search the TARDIS! Exterminate the Doctor!
哦,伙伴!你上当了
Oh, mate! You fell for the old switcheroo.
- 尴尬-那不是我的塔迪斯
- Awkward. - That's not my TARDIS.
我有一个备用的，
I had a spare one lying around,
所以我用变色龙的电路让它看起来像我的，
so I used the chameleon circuit to make it look like mine,
猜猜谁上当了?
and guess who fell for it?
你们
You guys.
我们会找到你的!
We shall find you!
我们控制了塔迪斯!
We have control of a TARDIS!
不你不对不起
No. You don't. Sorry.
更多的坏消息我给它编了个程序，让它自己折叠
More bad news. I've programmed it to fold in on itself
把自己送到虚空之心，
and send itself to the heart of the Void,
这当然会使它分裂，并在这个过程中摧毁你
which will of course break it apart and destroy you in the process.
谢谢你今天的帮助
Thanks for helping today.
一会儿见不到你了
Won't be seeing you later.
不你逃不掉的，博士!
No. You will not escape us, Doctor!
是的,我会的每一次
Yes, I will. Every time.
哦，太可怕了我感觉不舒服
Oh, that was horrible. I feel sick.
我这是怎么了?
What just happened to me?
我们成功了吗?
Did we do it?
我们做到了!
We did it!
戴立克流亡
Daleks all exiled.
现在，你要做很多解释
Now, you have got a lot of explaining to do.
我故意充当诱饵
I was deliberately acting as a decoy.
他们称他为人类的救世主，
They're calling him the saviour of humanity,
那个为我们所有人勇敢抵抗侵略者的人
the man who stood up to the invaders on behalf of us all.
现在，谣言四起
Now, as rumours intensify
他可能会被授予荣誉爵士头衔，
that he may be in line for an honorary knighthood,
杰克·罗伯逊在他美国的家中与我进行了交谈
Jack Robertson spoke to me from his home in the United States.
艾米丽，我做了任何男人-
Emily, I did what any man -
人，人的人-
person, human person -
在那种情况下是可以的
would do in those circumstances.
甚至有传言说你会重新竞选总统
There's even talk of a revived presidential run for you.
我不能回答这个问题
Well, I can't really answer to that.
-你能相信吗?-是的，我可以
- Can you believe that? - Yeah, I can.
我们应该去见见博士
We should go and meet the Doc.
是的
Yeah.
抱歉，忘了时间了
Sorry, lost track of time.
对了，格温·库珀向你问好
Gwen Cooper sends her love, by the way.
说她拿了戴立克的摩托车和她儿子的拳击手套
Says she took out a Dalek with a moped and her son's boxing gloves.
一个!
Hoo-hoo!
不管怎样，我要留在地球上追上她
Anyway, I'm going to stick around on Earth and catch up with her.
我会打电话给你
I'll call ya.
代我向格温问好好吧,再见!
Send my love to Gwen. OK, bye!
对了,家人,
Right, fam,
我想我们可以试试蛋白糖霜星系
I thought we could try the Meringue Galaxy.
这不是地方，这是餐厅
It's not a place, it's a restaurant
每一道菜都是蛋白霜
where every course is meringue.
和家具
And the furniture.
加上服务员!爱它!
Plus the waiters! Love it!
- 都准备好了吗?- 准备好了- 是的
- All set? - Ready. - Yep.
不
Nah.
我想我还是留在这里吧
I think I'm going to stay here.
是的
Yeah.
我的朋友需要我
Me mates need me.
我知道这听起来很蠢，但是…
And I know this sounds stupid, but...
. .我觉得我的星球需要我
..I feel like my planet needs me.
你得为之奋斗，对吧?
You've got to fight for it, right?
看,博士,之前…
Look, Doctor, before...
. .在我遇到你之前，我不知道我这辈子想做什么
..before I met you, I didn't know what I wanted to do with me life.
和…
And...
而现在……现在，我知道了
And now... And now, I know.
十个月
Ten months.
我回来得太晚了
I made it back too late.
错过了和你在一起的时光
Missed my time with you.
那么，我们是要拥抱还是? ?
So, are we hugging, or...?
你们两个呢?你打算……吗?
What about you two? Are you going to...?
留下来吗?是的,当然
Stay? Yeah, definitely.
是的!
Yes!
我还没准备好让你走
I'm not ready to let you go yet.
很好，不是吗?
That's all right, isn't it?
你已经说过了，所以…
You've said it now, so...
当然可以她需要你
Of course it's all right. She needs you.
- Yaz万岁! - 嗨
- Yes for Yaz! - Hey.
我走得够快了，你也忘了
You're getting over me leaving quick enough.
两颗心
Two hearts.
一个快乐…
One happy...
. .一个伤心
..one sad.
确保她不会惹上任何麻烦
Make sure she doesn't get in any trouble.
这很困难
It's going to be difficult.
我不在的时候，你要对这个星球负责
I'm holding you responsible for the planet while I'm away.
是的交易
Yeah. Deal.
格雷厄姆?
Graham?
听着，没事的，你知道的
Look, it's all right, you know.
我现在已经长大了，所以…你可以和他们一起去
I'm all grown up now, so... you can go with them.
是的,嗯…
Yeah, well...
是啊，你知道的，有很多东西值得探索，
Yeah, well, you know, there's lots to explore,
还有很多东西要看
so much more to see.
你知道的…
You know...
但是,嗯…
But, um...
我不想错过你，
I don't want to miss out on you,
你知道的，在这里没有你不会是…
you know, and being here without you ain't going to be...
. .相同的
..the same.
你知道，我会一直四处张望，
You know, I'll always be looking around, then,
对你说点什么，你知道吗?
to say stuff to you, you know?
你看，瑞安，你是我的家人
You see, Ryan, you're my family.
我记得，博士，你说过的话，
And I remember, Doc, what you said, you know,
我们……我们回来的时候不会是同一个人，你是对的
that we... we wouldn't come back the same people, and you're right.
只是不是我想的那种方式
Just not in the way I thought.
我准备好了我想……
I'm ready. I want to...
我想在家陪我孙子
I want to be at home with my grandson.
什么?
What?
我只是觉得这里应该是我一个人的地方
I just thought I'd have the place to myself, you know.
没有这样的运气
No such luck.
Yaz
Yaz.
我肯定很快就能见到你了?
I'm sure I'll see you soon, eh?
继续做人类的骄傲
Keep doing humanity proud.
我会想念你的
I'm going to miss you.
博士
Doc.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
对吧……
Right...
得了吧，儿子
Well, come on, son.
嘿…
Hey...
再见,家人
Bye, fam.
是的
Yeah.
对吧……
Right...
等待
Wait.
把这些可能会派上用场
Take these. Might come in handy.
哦助教
Oh. Ta.
哦!
Oh!
博士，我错了
And, Doc, I was wrong.
我们在谢菲尔德确实有外星人
We do get aliens in Sheffield.
我可以用塔迪斯回去，
I could always use the TARDIS to go back,
比你们晚到一小时
arrive an hour after you guys,
改变时间表
change the timeline.
那样我们就有更多的时间在一起了
Then we'd have more time together.
难过是正常的
It's OK to be sad.
好的,三,二,
OK, three, two,
一,发射!
one, go!
是的，继续，瑞恩!
Yes, go on, Ryan!
你做到了，儿子!
You're doing it, son!
继续,儿子!
Go on, son!
来吧!
Come on!
好吧
All right.
莱恩，你还好吗，儿子?
Ryan, you OK, son?
-是的是的- 是吗?
- Yeah. Yeah. - Yeah?
好吧，看更远的地方
Well, look, definitely further.
是的也许吧不,肯定
Yeah. Maybe. No, definitely.
我之前在网上查过…
I was looking online earlier...
芬兰的一个村庄发生了一些奇怪的事情
Some weird stuff going on in a village in Finland.
食人魔入侵，当地人这么说
Troll invasion, so the locals are saying.
是的，我看到了
Yeah, I saw that.
你知道，韩国有个采石场关闭了
And, you know, there's a quarry in Korea that's shut down
因为工人们正在报告
because the workers are reporting
他们看到沙砾动物活过来了
they saw gravel creatures come to life.
灵媒
Psychic paper.
-是的-这些能让我们去任何地方
- Yeah. - These will get us in anywhere.
是的,芬兰、韩国……
Yeah, Finland, Korea...
-那我们还等什么?-我还没说完呢
- Well, then, what are we waiting for? - I'm not done here yet.
是的,但是,你看……我的意思是,这……
Yeah, but, look... I mean, this...
你会全身青一块紫一块的
You'll be black and blue.
我不知道你有没有听说过我，我是莱恩·辛克莱
I don't know if you heard about me, but I'm Ryan Sinclair.
我和我的伙伴们，把所有东西都送走了
Me and me mates, we saw off everything
从巨型蜘蛛到意识宇宙
from giant spiders to a conscious universe.
我们打了Cybermen,
We fought Cybermen,
Skithra Morax…
Skithra, Morax...
. .强大的pt
..the mighty Pting.
光靠一辆自行车可吓不倒我
It's going to take more than a bike to scare me off.
对吧，爷爷?
Ain't that right, Grandad?
是的
Yeah.
正确的,那么好吧，那就来吧跳上
Right, then. Well, come on, then. Jump on, then.
-你没事吧?-是的
- You all right? - Yeah.
是啊，只是阳光照进了我的眼睛
Yeah, uh, just got the sun in me eyes.
是的,我也是
Yeah, me too.
好吧，再试几次我们就能去拯救世界了?
Right, a few more tries and we'll go and save the world, eh?
-是的-是的
- Yeah. - Yeah.
来吧，准备好
Here we go, get ready.
三,二,一…
Three, two, one...
走吧!继续,瑞安
Go! Go on, Ryan.
是啊!继续,孩子!
Yeah! Go on, son!
你做到了，伙计!
You're doing it, mate!